<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Accueil on Révisions LLCE</title>
    <link>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Accueil on Révisions LLCE</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>fr</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>After the Revolution</title>
      <link>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/civilisation/the-american-revolution/after-revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/civilisation/the-american-revolution/after-revolution/</guid>
      <description>The outcome of the war The death toll is hard to tell precisely. There may have been around 25.000 dead mostly because of the war itself, but also because of the violence between patriots and loyalists.
Crops and harbors got severely damaged. The break with Great Britain caused a loss of opportunities for the American exportations. This young nation’s economy suffered from a huge business deficit. American production fall. It led to important indebtedness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auxiliaires et verbes</title>
      <link>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/linguistique/le-groupe-verbal/auxiliaires-et-verbes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/linguistique/le-groupe-verbal/auxiliaires-et-verbes/</guid>
      <description>Définition Il y a deux catégories d’éléments verbaux qui peuvent entrer dans la composition d’un GV : les auxiliaires et les verbes.
Les auxiliaires se définissent par deux caractéristiques syntaxiques que les verbes n’ont pas.
 Leur négation se forme par l&amp;rsquo;ajout de not, contracté en n’t dans isn’t, can’t, etc. Ils permettent le passage de la forme déclarative à la forme interrogative par inversion avec le groupe sujet : Your brother can swim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be, have et get</title>
      <link>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/linguistique/le-groupe-verbal/be-have-et-get/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/linguistique/le-groupe-verbal/be-have-et-get/</guid>
      <description>Be et have, auxiliaires ou verbes ? Be et have sont polyvalents, ils possèdent tantôt les caractéristiques syntaxiques des auxiliaires (négation et interrogation directes, i.e. sans do), tantôt celles des verbes.
 Be a le plus souvent les caractéristiques des auxiliaires :   He is reading. He is not reading. Is he reading ? / He is English. He is not English. Is he English ?
 Cependant, dans He is English, be est en même temps un verbe, étant donné qu&amp;rsquo;il est le seul élément de nature verbale de la proposition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boston campaign</title>
      <link>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/civilisation/the-american-revolution/boston-campaign/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/civilisation/the-american-revolution/boston-campaign/</guid>
      <description>It is often said that the American war of Independence began with the British on April 19th, 1775, during Boston siege (battles of Concord and Lexington) but the first event that triggered the popular reaction to english invasion started with what’s known as the Powder Alarm.
On September 1st, 1774, british soldiers confiscated powder supplies and weapons from the militia during a surprise action near Boston. This expedition alarmed the entire country and american patriots ran into action, persuaded war had begun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colonial relationships with Great Britain</title>
      <link>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/civilisation/the-american-revolution/colonial-relationships/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/civilisation/the-american-revolution/colonial-relationships/</guid>
      <description>British imperialism After the Seven Years’ war, British authorities started to think about their empire. Between 1770 and 1782, the Tories in power dreamed of strengthening colonial domination and centralisation. Advocating protectionism, they wanted to strictly apply a mercantilist policy by reinforcing commercial monopoly, encouraging maritim companies and fighting against contraband traffic (= commerce de contrebande). Tories had to face the Whigs’ opposition, who were in favor of free trade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confederation period, 1781-1789 </title>
      <link>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/civilisation/the-american-revolution/confederation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/civilisation/the-american-revolution/confederation/</guid>
      <description>Since 1781, a new Congress took place, replacing the Second Continental Congress. However, the members of this new assembly were the same as before.
The Congress’ fields of competence were limited: money, citizenship, positions, units of measure. A money was born in 1785, the dollar, to replace British pounds, but mostly the different foreign moneys that circulated throughout North America. The propagation of banknotes continued after the war.
Expansion to the West Territories west of the Appalachians Mountains, attributed to the United States by the Treaty of Paris, were the stake of rivalries between States.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Context: the Thirteen British Colonies around 1775</title>
      <link>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/civilisation/the-american-revolution/context/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/civilisation/the-american-revolution/context/</guid>
      <description>Geography The colonies were created between early 17th century and the first third of the 18th century on hundreds of kilometers along the Atlantic coast. Communication between them was often slow and complicated: the existing roads were in a pretty bad shape and there were only few bridges.
Population Around 1770, the Thirteen Colonies’ total population was approximately 2.2 million inhabitants. Since their creation, the colonies had a strong demographic growth thanks to immigration but also a high birth rate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discours rapporté</title>
      <link>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/linguistique/le-groupe-verbal/discours-rapport%C3%A9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/linguistique/le-groupe-verbal/discours-rapport%C3%A9/</guid>
      <description>Le discours direct et le discours indirect (ou style direct / indirect) sont deux variétés du discours rapporté :
 Bert said, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m listening.&amp;rdquo;
Bert said that he was listening.
 Le discours rapporté peut être du discours au sens étroit : il consiste alors en des paroles que l&amp;rsquo;on rapporte. Mais il peut également consister en des pensées, sentiments, impressions, opinions, etc. Dans ce dernier cas, le discours est généralement rapporté par l&amp;rsquo;intermédiaire d&amp;rsquo;un verbe ou d&amp;rsquo;une expression du type think, know, feel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/civilisation/the-american-revolution/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/civilisation/the-american-revolution/introduction/</guid>
      <description>The American Revolution is a time of political changes that occurred after 1763 in the Thirteen Colonies of North America. It led to the American war of Independence against the British between 1775 and 1783, resulting in the independence from Great Britain and the establishment of the United States of America.
In order to defray the costs of the Seven Years’ War (1756-1763, a global conflict that involved every European great power of the time and split the continent into two coalitions), Great Britain taxed its American colonies without them being consulted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/linguistique/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/linguistique/introduction/</guid>
      <description>Rappel de quelques notions essentielles.
Phrase et énoncé La phrase peut être une simple abstraction. Elle ne définit qu’un assemblage de mots selon les règles de la syntaxe, en dehors de tout discours. L’énoncé quant à lui est ce que produit le locuteur et ce qu’entend l’auditeur dans une situation donnée : la situation d’énonciation. Il est composé d’un ou plusieurs segments correspondant à des phrases et est un échantillon “réel” de langage, c&amp;rsquo;est le porteur d&amp;rsquo;un message.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portail de la civilisation</title>
      <link>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/civilisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/civilisation/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer : Ce que vous trouverez ici est principalement une traduction allégée et retravaillée des différentes pages Wikipédia.
 The American Revolution  Introduction Context: the Thirteen British Colonies around 1775 Colonial relationships with Great Britain Rise of opposition Boston campaign   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portail de la linguistique</title>
      <link>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/linguistique/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/linguistique/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Le groupe verbal  Auxiliaires et verbes Be, have et get Présent Prétérit Discours rapporté   Le contenu de ce portail est fortement inspiré de la Grammaire explicative de l&amp;rsquo;anglais, par Larreya et Rivière. Certains passages sont allégés et retravaillés.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Présent</title>
      <link>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/linguistique/le-groupe-verbal/pr%C3%A9sent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/linguistique/le-groupe-verbal/pr%C3%A9sent/</guid>
      <description>Il n&amp;rsquo;existe en anglais que deux temps grammaticaux, ou tenses : le présent et le prétérit. Nous verrons ici le présent.
Comme evoqué dans les chapitres précédents, l&amp;rsquo;élément présent ou prétérit est toujours, dans un groupe verbal, porté par le premier terme : verbe dans le cas des formes simples, auxiliaire dans les autres. Les éléments présent et prétérit ont toujours le même sens fondamental, qu&amp;rsquo;ils soient portés par un verbe ou un auxiliaire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prétérit</title>
      <link>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/linguistique/le-groupe-verbal/pr%C3%A9t%C3%A9rit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/linguistique/le-groupe-verbal/pr%C3%A9t%C3%A9rit/</guid>
      <description>Forme régulière du prétérit simple I / he / we worked (base verbale + terminaison -ed)
Prononcer le -ed du prétérit    /ɪd/ ou /əd/ (selon variété d&amp;rsquo;anglais) /t/ /d/     après les sons /t/ ou /d/ après les consonnes sourdes /p/ /k/ /f/ etc. après les consonnes sonores /b/ /g/ /v/ etc. et après les voyelles    Le choix entre /t/ et /d/ dépend de la facilité de prononciation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rise of opposition</title>
      <link>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/civilisation/the-american-revolution/rise-of-opposition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/civilisation/the-american-revolution/rise-of-opposition/</guid>
      <description>Years 1763-1774 saw the rise of colonial opposition in response to British claims, marked by a series of economical laws, quickly repealed by central power.
The Seven Years’ War consequences The Seven Years’ War (1756-1763) was a conflict between European powers and completely emptied the Crown’s cashbox. After the war, the British debt was up to £317.000.000. The government decided to keep an army of thousands of men in the colonies, the cost being around £300.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The American war of Independence, 1775-1783</title>
      <link>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/civilisation/the-american-revolution/the-american-war-of-independence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/civilisation/the-american-revolution/the-american-war-of-independence/</guid>
      <description>In the beginning of year 1775, Americans plundered (piller) armories and organized militias. However, the american forces were way inferior compared to the british army, quality and means included. Violent actions multiplied: in a speech made in St. John church in Richmond, Virginia, Patrick Henry declared “Give me liberty, or give me death!”.
First fights in the North, 1775 The first battle opposing British soldiers to Americans was the Lexington and Concord one, a few kilometers west of Boston (April 1775): this skirmish (= escarmouche), which end was in favor of the insurgents, caused 73 British deaths and 49 American deaths.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The federalist period, 1789-1801</title>
      <link>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/civilisation/the-american-revolution/federalist-period/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/civilisation/the-american-revolution/federalist-period/</guid>
      <description>The new Congress got elected in January 1789. In April, George Washington was chosen unanimously to be the United States’ first President and installed his office in New-York, provisory capital of the country, where he swore on the bible. In September, a Bill of Rights was added to the Constitution by the Congress, it got ratified in December 1791.
Debates went on about the role of the federal state: federalists joined Alexander Hamilton and desired a strong federal power; they were against egalitarianism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The figures of the American Revolution</title>
      <link>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/civilisation/the-american-revolution/figures-of-revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolwenndeumie.github.io/civilisation/the-american-revolution/figures-of-revolution/</guid>
      <description>The Founding Fathers “Founding Fathers” designate the men thanks to whom the American Constitution was born. They are seen as heroes. Those about sixty men shared numerous common points: all white, a majority being Christian. They read the Lumières’ philosophers and some were freemasons (= franc-maçons). They are experienced and intelligent men, mostly jurists or notables. Lots of them served in the continental army to high commanding positions.
The most famous had political positions, first in their own States, then higher: George Washington, John Adams, Thomas Jefferson and James Madison where the first four POTUS.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>